Okay, so let's summarize everything
we've learned in this section.
So SQS is a queuing service in AWS
and we can have multiple producers into an SQS queue.
The messages are going to be kept
up to 14 days in the queue, then deleted.
Consumers can read these messages
and they will share the reads.
So they will split the reads
and then once a message is read and processed
then it's going to be deleted.
So when a consumer is done, the message is gone.
It's used to decouple applications within AWS.
So anytime you see queuing and decoupling, think SQS.
SNS is a notification service in AWS.
And so we have producers and subscribers.
So it could be email, Lambda, SQS queues, HTTP, mobile
and if you have multiple subscribers onto one SNS topic
then SNS will send a message to all of them.
SNS doesn't retain any message
so it's not a durable store of messages
and it's going to be used again for pub/sub,
for subscribers, for topics and notifications within AWS.
Finally, we've seen Kinesis
which is a real time data streaming service
which is going to have some data persistence
and also you can run analytics
on top of Kinesis in real time.
And finally, we have Amazon MQ
which is a managed message broker
for Active MQ and RabbitMQ in the cloud.
So if you want to migrate from on-premises
to the cloud and use the MQTT, AMQP,
or other kind of protocols, this is a service for you.
So that's it for this section.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next section.